This is a mock response from DeepSeek API for
development mode.
Your prompt was: " Based on the following topic,
generate a comprehensive and engaging text of
approximately 8000 characters.
The content should be well-structured,
informative, and suitable for narration in a
video: i want to be a witch.
The text should include: - A compelling
introduction - Detailed exploration of the topic -
Interesting facts or insights - A meaningful
conclusion Please ensure the content is factually
accurate and engaging.
" In a real deployment with a valid API key,
this would connect to the DeepSeek API and return
an actual generated response.
For now, this placeholder text is shown instead.
To use the actual DeepSeek API, please set the
DEEPSEEK_API_KEY environment variable with your
API key.